<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<course
  xmlns="https://csmp.missouriwestern.edu"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="https://csmp.missouriwestern.edu/xml/curriculum/course.xsd">
  <college>LA</college>
  <subject>CSC</subject>
  <number>201</number>
  <title>Microcomputer Applications </title>
  <offered>fall</offered>
  <offered>spring</offered>
  <scheduleType>lecture</scheduleType>
  <catalogDescription>
Applications of productivity software such as Microsoft Office Word, Excel, Access, and PowerPoint for careers, school, and home. Impact of technology on society by computer information systems, networks, e-commerce, and the Internet is included. Previous computer experience recommended.
  </catalogDescription>
  <prerequisites>
  </prerequisites>
  <objectives>
    <objective>The  primary  purpose  of  this  course  is  to  prepare  students  who  have  not  had  a  background  in computers to be better consumers and more productive in their college work or job performance. </objective>
    <objective>Specific  topics  include  advanced  word  processing  techniques,  multi-media,  Internet,  e-mail, personal computers, and basic concepts of networking, databases, and spreadsheet topics.</objective>
    <objective>A  strong  emphasis  is  placed  on  issues  of  ethics,  societal  impacts,  and  appropriate  use  of  all technologies that are covered. </objective>
  </objectives>
  <outline>
    <topic>Introduction to Windows
    </topic>
    <topic>Microsoft Word
        <topic>Document Presentation: Editing and Formatting</topic>
        <topic>Document Productivity: Working with Tables and Mail Merge</topic>
        <topic>ollaboration and Research: Communicating and Producing Professional  Papers</topic>
    </topic>
    <topic>Microsoft Excel
        <topic>Introduction to Excel: What Is a Spreadsheet? </topic>
        <topic>Formulas and Functions: Performing Quantitative Analysis </topic>
        <topic>Charts: Depicting Data Visually  </topic>
        <topic>Datasets and Tables: Managing Large Volumes of Data </topic>
    </topic>
    <topic>Microsoft Access
        <topic> Introduction to Access: Finding Your Way Through an Access Database</topic>
        <topic>Tables and Queries in Relational Databases: Designing Databases and Extracting Data</topic>
        <topic> Customize, Analyze, and Summarize Query Data: Using Queries to Make Decisions</topic>
        <topic>Creating and Using Professional Forms and Reports: Moving Beyond Tables and Queries </topic>
    </topic>
    <topic>Microsoft Powerpoint
        <topic>Introduction to PowerPoint: Creating a Basic Presentation</topic>
        <topic>Presentation Development: Planning and Preparing a Presentation</topic>
        <topic>Presentation Design: Illustrations and Infographics</topic>
        <topic>PowerPoint Rich Media Tools: Enhancing with Multimedia</topic>
    </topic>
    <topic>Application Integration
    </topic>
  </outline>
</course>
