<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<course
  xmlns="https://csmp.missouriwestern.edu"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="https://csmp.missouriwestern.edu/xml/curriculum/course.xsd">
  <college>LA</college>
  <subject>CSC</subject>
  <number>200</number>
  <title>Computer Systems and Architecture</title>
  <offered>fall</offered>
  <offered>spring</offered>
  <scheduleType>lecture</scheduleType>
  <catalogDescription>
	 This course will cover applications of productivity software such as Microsoft Office® Word, Excel, Access, and PowerPoint for careers, school, and home. Impact of technology on society by computer information systems, networks, e-commerce, and the Internet is included. 
  </catalogDescription>
  <prerequisites>
  </prerequisites>
  <objectives>
    <objective>Emphasizes problem-solving, critical thinking, andanalysis to challenge students to find efficient and effective solutions to business situations. </objective>
    <objective>Understand the broad picture of Information Technology and the scope of the different career paths.</objective>
    <objective>Understand the basic hardware configurations and parts of a personal computer.</objective>
    <objective>Understand the different types of softwareapplications; operating systems, production application, software as service applications.</objective>
    <objective>Understand the basic database concepts and how they relate to business as well as how businesses rely on computer networks in day to day operations.</objective>
    <objective>Effectively work together in teams.</objective>
    <objective></objective>
    <objective></objective>
    <objective></objective>
  </objectives>
  <outline>
    <topic>Information Systems in Perspective
      <topic>An Introduction to Information Systems in Organizations. </topic>
    </topic>
    <topic>Technology
      <topic>Hardware and Software.</topic>
      <topic>Database Systems and Business Intelligence.</topic>
      <topic>Telecommunications, the Internet, Intranets, and Extranets.</topic>
    </topic>
    <topic>Business Information Systems
      <topic>Electronic and Mobile Commerce and Enterprise Systems.</topic>
      <topic>Information and Decision Support Systems.</topic>
      <topic>Knowledge Management and Specialized Information Systems.</topic>
    </topic>
    <topic>Systems Development and Social Issues
      <topic>Systems Development</topic>
    </topic>
    <topic>Information Systems in Business and Society
      <topic>The Personal and Social Impact of Computers.</topic>
    </topic>
    <topic>Hardware Configuration and Topics
      <topic>Personal computer organization, number theory, operating systems</topic>
    </topic>
  </outline>
</course>
