<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<course
  xmlns="https://csmp.missouriwestern.edu"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="https://csmp.missouriwestern.edu/xml/curriculum/course.xsd">
  <college>LA</college>
  <subject>ACT</subject>
  <number>405</number>
  <title>Business Intelligence</title>
  <offered>discretion</offered>
  <scheduleType>lecture</scheduleType>
  <catalogDescription>
Students learn how to make better business decisions, use fewer resources, and improve the company's bottom line by developing and using a data warehouse. This course provides an overview of business intelligence and data warehousing and gives students a look at all the major facets of developing and using a data warehouse to make effective business decisions.
  </catalogDescription>
  <prerequisites>
    <prerequisiteCourse minimumGrade="C"><subject>CSC</subject><number>305</number></prerequisiteCourse>
  </prerequisites>
  <objectives>
    <objective>Use application development tools and techniques in a hands-on learning environment to develop web—based database Bl applications.</objective>
    <objective>Utilized spreadsheet and database skills learned in previous coursework to create internet based portal for use by business decision makers</objective>
    <objective>Develop an understanding of the importance of security measures that must be taken toensure information integrity and privacy in applications.</objective>
    <objective>Develop an awareness of the importance of quality in application development.</objective>
    <objective>Become an informed developer of information portals.</objective>
    <objective>Usage of the technology current in the industry.</objective>
    <objective>Become familiar with the concepts and techniques used to implement BusinessIntelligence.</objective>
    <objective>Understand the importance of skill requirements and team dynamics.</objective>
    <objective>Understand the critical success factors and goals for a Business Intelligence system</objective>
  </objectives>
  <outline>
    <topic></topic>
  </outline>
</course>
