<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<course
  xmlns="https://csmp.missouriwestern.edu"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="https://csmp.missouriwestern.edu/xml/curriculum/course.xsd">
  <college>LA</college>
  <subject>CSC</subject>
  <number>318</number>
  <title>Simulation and Modeling</title>
  <offered>spring</offered>
  <scheduleType>lecture</scheduleType>
  <catalogDescription>
An introduction to computerized simulations. Focus is on the architecture and development of time-step and event-sequenced models used extensively by industry and government. Other topics include process generators for random events, the development of computerized games for management training, and current simulation research.  
  </catalogDescription>
  <prerequisites>
    <prerequisiteCourse minimumGrade="C"><subject>CSC</subject><number>285</number></prerequisiteCourse>
  </prerequisites>
  <objectives>
    <objective>Create a simulation that has a time stepped architecture.</objective>
    <objective>Identify  the  appropriate  time  step  for  their  simulation  architecture  to  model  the  process being simulated. </objective>
    <objective>Identify the random process generators needed to appropriately model the process being simulated.</objective>
    <objective>Understand the relationship between the time step and the random processes</objective>
    <objective>Understand  the  probability  and  statistical  methods  necessary  to  create  finite  random process generators.</objective>
    <objective>Develop and program the random processes generators supporting the random activities in a simulation.  First Introduction is to generators with finite outcomes.</objective>
    <objective>Develop a time stepped simulation in an Object Oriented programming language context.  </objective>
    <objective>Design and develop Event Based Simulation Architectures.</objective>
    <objective>Identify key events in a process so that the process can be adequately modeled/simulated with an event based architecture.</objective>
    <objective>Identify  and  create  processes  for  each  event  that  represents  the  event’s  impact  on  the simulation space.</objective>
    <objective>Understand the structure of classic game types (.i.e.single shooter first person, multiplayer, etc</objective>
    <objective>Design  and  develop  a  two  player  game  using  simple  AI  techniques  to  simulate  the movements by each player. </objective>
    <objective>Understand minimax theory as applied in a gaming strategy. </objective>
  </objectives>
  <outline>
    <topic>Serial Model Execution
      <topic>Process generators for time step enviornments</topic>
    </topic>
    <topic>Probability Review
      <topic>Generation of process generators from frequency data</topic>
    </topic>
    <topic>Object Oriented Time Step Simulations
      <topic>Drivers for Simulations in object oriented architectures </topic>
    </topic>
    <topic>Event Based Simulations
      <topic>Events</topic>
      <topic>Event Queue</topic>
      <topic>Clock</topic>
    </topic>
    <topic>Random Process predicting time till next event
      <topic>Normal distributio</topic>
      <topic>Poisson Processes</topic>
    </topic>
    <topic>Artificial Intelligence in gaming architectures
      <topic>Minimax</topic>
      <topic>Markov Chains</topic>
      <topic>Finite State Machines</topic>
    </topic>
  </outline>
</course>
