<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<course
  xmlns="https://csmp.missouriwestern.edu"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="https://csmp.missouriwestern.edu/xml/curriculum/course.xsd"
  creditHoursLecture="1"
  workloadHoursLecture="1">
  <college>LA</college>
  <subject>ACT</subject>
  <number>490</number>
  <title>Computer Science Career Preparation</title>
  <offered>fall</offered>
  <scheduleType>lecture</scheduleType>
  <catalogDescription>In this course students will begin applying their MWSU education towards building a career in CS. Students will learn how to navigate a career path in CS, explore alternative career paths, and explore opportunities for continuing education and professional development. Students will develop application materials and attempt entrance, exit, and / or certification exams in preparation for graduation, applying to jobs, and applying to graduate schools. 
  </catalogDescription>
  <prerequisites>
  </prerequisites>
  <objectives>
    <objective>Determine what types of jobs in CS best match their short and long term career and professional development goals</objective>
    <objective>Locate and navigate resources for finding CS jobs in their desired location</objective>
    <objective>Effectively communicate their skill set and value as an employee to potential employers through letters, resumes, networking, interviews, and other means</objective>
    <objective>Explain the concept that because you can do it, it doesn’t mean you should do it.
      <covers standard="acm-csec2017" knowledgeArea="2/7" id="1"/>
    </objective>
    <objective>Paraphrase professional ethics and codes of conduct from prominent professional societies, such as ACM, IEEE-CS, AIS and (ISC)
      <covers standard="acm-csec2017" knowledgeArea="8/3" id="2"/>
    </objective>
    <objective>Describe ways in which decision-making algorithms could over-represent or under-represent majority and minority groups in society.
      <covers standard="acm-csec2017" knowledgeArea="8/3" id="3"/>
    </objective>
    <objective>Locate and utilize resources for continuing education and professional development to gain or improve specific skillsets in CS or transition in to other career fields (ex. Law)</objective>
    <objective>Prepare effectively for certification exams, assessments, and technical interviews</objective>
  </objectives>
  <outline>
    <topic>Searching for CS employment opportunities</topic>
    <topic>Emerging and popular CS skillsets and technologies</topic>
    <topic>Communication
        <topic>Developing CS resumes</topic>
        <topic>Developing CS cover letters</topic>
        <topic>Developing a project portfolio</topic>
        <topic>Applying to graduate schools</topic>
        <topic>Developing a web and social media presence</topic>
    </topic>
    <topic>Networking
        <topic>Professional organizations</topic>
        <topic>Conferences, job fairs, and other professional gatherings</topic>
    </topic>
    <topic>Professional ethics and employment regulations</topic>
    <topic>Preparing for entrance, exit, and certification exams</topic>
  </outline>
</course>
