<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<course
  xmlns="https://csmp.missouriwestern.edu"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="https://csmp.missouriwestern.edu/xml/curriculum/course.xsd">
  <college>LA</college>
  <subject>CSC</subject>
  <number>410</number>
  <title>Network Security Technologies</title>
  <offered>fall</offered>
  <scheduleType>lecture</scheduleType>
  <catalogDescription>
This course covers various facets of network security and the tools that are available to secure and monitor networks. Topics include commercial and open source security tools, public-key cryptography, firewalls, authentication, intrusion detection, control of malicious code, OS hardening fundamentals, and security assessment.
  </catalogDescription>
  <prerequisites>
    <prerequisiteCourse minimumGrade="C"><subject>CSC</subject><number>294</number></prerequisiteCourse>
  </prerequisites>
  <objectives>
    <objective>demonstrate the ability to implement software that is robust against common security attacks
        <covers standard="acm-csec2017" knowledgeArea="2/2" id="3"/></objective>
    <objective>understand the capabilities of modern cryptographic systems and apply them appropriately
        <covers standard="acm-csec2017" knowledgeArea="1/1" id="1"/>
    </objective>
    <objective>decompose system security requirements into confidentiality, integrity, and availability components
        <covers standard="acm-csec2017" knowledgeArea="5" id="2"/>
    </objective>
    <objective>assess threats to and vulnerabilities of a computer system
        <covers standard="acm-csec2017" knowledgeArea="3/1" id="1"/>
    </objective>
    <objective>evaluate the level of risk associated with various types of threats</objective>
    <objective>justify appropriate countermeasures in response to identified threats</objective>
    <objective>identify legal and ethical ramifications of policy decisions and defend those decision</objective>
    <objective>distinguish desired system features (policy) from their implementation (mechanism)</objective>
    <objective>design a security plan for an instructor-supplied system description</objective>
    <objective>study the basic concepts in crytography
      <covers standard="acm-csec2017" knowledgeArea="1/1" id="1"/>
    </objective>
    <objective>study the advanced concepts in crytography
      <covers standard="acm-csec2017" knowledgeArea="1/1" id="2"/>
    </objective>
    <objective>Mathematical background
      <covers standard="acm-csec2017" knowledgeArea="1/1" id="3"/>
    </objective>
    <objective>Historical ciphers
      <covers standard="acm-csec2017" knowledgeArea="1/1" id="4"/>
    </objective>
    <objective>Symmetric (private key) ciphers
      <covers standard="acm-csec2017" knowledgeArea="1/1" id="5"/>
    </objective>
    <objective>Asymmetric (public-key) ciphers
      <covers standard="acm-csec2017" knowledgeArea="1/1" id="6"/>
    </objective>
  </objectives>
  <outline>
    <topic>Encryption/decryption, sender authentication, data integrity, non-repudiation
      <covers standard="acm-csec2017" knowledgeArea="1/1" id="1"/>
    </topic>
    <topic>Attack classification (ciphertext-only, known plaintext, chosen plaintext, chosen ciphertext)
      <covers standard="acm-csec2017" knowledgeArea="1/1" id="1"/>
    </topic>
    <topic>Secret key (symmetric), cryptography and public-key (asymmetric) cryptography
      <covers standard="acm-csec2017" knowledgeArea="1/1" id="1"/>
    </topic>
    <topic>Information-theoretic security (one-time pad, Shannon Theorem)
      <covers standard="acm-csec2017" knowledgeArea="1/1" id="1"/>
    </topic>
    <topic>Computational security
      <covers standard="acm-csec2017" knowledgeArea="1/1" id="1"/>
    </topic>
    <topic>Advanced protocols: Zero-knowledge proofs, and protocols, Secret sharing, Committment, Oblivious transfer, Secure multiparty computation
      <covers standard="acm-csec2017" knowledgeArea="1/1" id="2"/>
    </topic>
    <topic>Advanced recent developments: fully homomorphic encryption, obfuscation, quantum cryptography, and KLJN scheme.
      <covers standard="acm-csec2017" knowledgeArea="1/1" id="2"/>
    </topic>
    <topic>Essential mathematical topics in understanding encryption: Modular arithmetic, Fermat, Euler theorems, Primitive roots, discrete log problem, Primality testing, factoring large integers, Elliptic curves, lattices and hard lattice problems, Abstract algebra, finite fields, and Information theory
      <covers standard="acm-csec2017" knowledgeArea="1/1" id="3"/>
    </topic>
    <topic>Historical ciphers (Shift cipher, affine cipher, substitution cipher, Vigenere cipher, ROT-13, and Hill cipher, Enigma machine, and others) and their applications.
      <covers standard="acm-csec2017" knowledgeArea="1/1" id="4"/>
    </topic>
    <topic>System Security: hacker behavior, intrusion and anomaly detection, hacker and admin tools
    </topic>
    <topic>Networks and Infrastructure: TCP/IP, Denial of Service, IPSEC, TLS/SSL</topic>
    <topic>Basic Cryptography: Shared key crypto (AES/DES), Public Key Crypto (RSA), hashes</topic>
    <topic>Crypto software: Open SSL library, applications (authentication, digital signatures)</topic>
    <topic>Trust and Configuration management</topic>
    <topic>Malicious code: buffer overflows, viruses, worms, protection mechanisms</topic>
    <topic>Covert channels</topic>
  </outline>
</course>
