<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<course
  xmlns="https://csmp.missouriwestern.edu"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="https://csmp.missouriwestern.edu/xml/curriculum/course.xsd">
  <college>LA</college>
  <subject>SEC</subject>
  <number>435</number>
  <title>Host and Network Security</title>
  <offered>spring</offered>
  <scheduleType>lecture</scheduleType>
  <catalogDescription>
stub
  </catalogDescription>
  <prerequisites>
  </prerequisites>

  <objectives>
    <objective>Discuss the need to update software to fix security vulnerabilities.
      <covers standard="acm-csec2017" knowledgeArea="2/5" id="1"/>
    </objective>
    <objective>Explain the need to test software after an update but before the patch is distributed.
      <covers standard="acm-csec2017" knowledgeArea="2/5" id="2"/>
    </objective>
    <objective>Explain the relationship among a security group, system configuration, and procedures to maintain the security of the system.
      <covers standard="acm-csec2017" knowledgeArea="5" id="6"/>
    </objective>
    <objective>Describe the components and interfaces of a networking standard provided.
      <covers standard="acm-csec2017" knowledgeArea="4" id="5"/>
    </objective>
    <objective>Discuss how the Internet 5 layer model can be viewed as software components and interfaces that represent levels of services encapsulated by lower-level services.
      <covers standard="acm-csec2017" knowledgeArea="4" id="11"/>
    </objective>
    <objective>Explain how connection attacks can be understood in terms of attacks on software component interfaces.
      <covers standard="acm-csec2017" knowledgeArea="4" id="13"/>
    </objective>
    <objective>Explain how transmission attacks are often implemented as attacks on components that provide the service of relaying information.
      <covers standard="acm-csec2017" knowledgeArea="4" id="16"/>
    </objective>
    <objective>Describe an attack on a specified node in a TCP/IP network given the description of a vulnerability.
      <covers standard="acm-csec2017" knowledgeArea="4" id="17"/>
    </objective>
    <objective>Explain why transmission attacks can often be viewed as connection attacks on network components (physical or software).
      <covers standard="acm-csec2017" knowledgeArea="4" id="18"/>
    </objective>
    <objective>Explain the goals of end-to-end data security.
      <covers standard="acm-csec2017" knowledgeArea="1/1" id="6"/>
    </objective>
    <objective>Discuss how intrusion detection systems contribute to security.
      <covers standard="acm-csec2017" knowledgeArea="5" id="13"/>
    </objective>
    <objective>Describe the limits of anti-malware software such as antivirus programs.
      <covers standard="acm-csec2017" knowledgeArea="5" id="14"/>
    </objective>
    <objective>Discuss uses of system monitoring.
      <covers standard="acm-csec2017" knowledgeArea="5" id="15"/>
    </objective>
    <objective>Discuss the importance of documenting proper installation and configuration of a system.
      <covers standard="acm-csec2017" knowledgeArea="5" id="22"/>
    </objective>
    <objective>Be able to write host and network intrusions documentation.
      <covers standard="acm-csec2017" knowledgeArea="5" id="23"/>
    </objective>
    <objective>Be able to explain the security implications of unclear or incomplete documentation of system operation.
      <covers standard="acm-csec2017" knowledgeArea="5" id="24"/>
    </objective>
    <objective>Explain why a hardware device is always modeled a physical component.
      <covers standard="acm-csec2017" knowledgeArea="4" id="6"/>
    </objective>
    <objective>List several examples of physical component interfaces with their associated vulnerabilities.
      <covers standard="acm-csec2017" knowledgeArea="4" id="7"/>
    </objective>
    <objective>Describe an exploit for a vulnerability of a physical interface provided.
      <covers standard="acm-csec2017" knowledgeArea="4" id="8"/>
    </objective>
    <objective>Discuss how TCP/IP as a service is represented by different interfaces in different software systems.
      <covers standard="acm-csec2017" knowledgeArea="4" id="12"/>
    </objective>
    <objective>Describe how an implementation could protect itself from a specified vulnerability in a specified standard interface.
      <covers standard="acm-csec2017" knowledgeArea="4" id="15"/>
    </objective>
    <objective>Explain what resilience is and identify an environment in which it is important.
      <covers standard="acm-csec2017" knowledgeArea="5" id="16"/>
    </objective>
  </objectives>
  <outline>
    <topic>Introduction
    </topic>
  </outline>
</course>
