<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<course
  xmlns="https://csmp.missouriwestern.edu"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="https://csmp.missouriwestern.edu/xml/curriculum/course.xsd">
  <college>LA</college>
  <subject>CSC</subject>
  <number>615</number>
  <title>Routing and Switching</title>
  <offered>spring</offered>
  <scheduleType>lecture</scheduleType>
  <catalogDescription>
This course introduces students to the vendor-specific knowledge in designing, implementing, maintaining, and troubleshooting local and wide-area enterprise networks. Students will acquire understanding of network infrastructures and protocols, and how they work together in practice. In addition, they will learn about the concept of quality of service (QoS) elements and their applicability, securing networks by setting up firewalls, and configuring wireless controllers and access points. Students will also learn to work with IPv6. After the completion of this course, students may apply the knowledge and skills they have learned to related technologies such as cloud, data center, and advanced network security.
  </catalogDescription>
  <prerequisites>
  </prerequisites>
  <objectives>
    <objective>To understand, master and secure network communications on multiple scales: intra-network communication (LAN Switching Technologies) inter-network communications (Routing Technologies), and long-distance communications (WAN Technologies), and infrastructure services, security and management.</objective>
    <objective>To secure and manage infrastructure services.</objective>
  </objectives>
  <outline>
    <topic>Network Fundamentals
	<topic>Understanding OSI Model, concepts of IP (IPv4 and IPv6), routing, and purpose of subnetting</topic>
	<topic>Configuring Ethernet interfaces</topic>
	<topic>Using CISCO Packet Tracer to create network topologies and imitate computer networks</topic>
	<topic></topic>
    </topic>
    <topic>LAN Switching Technologies
	<topic>Understanding of common LAN protocols</topic>
	<topic>Working with Cisco IOS</topic>
	<topic>Managing MAC address tables</topic>
	<topic>Securing LAN switches</topic>
    </topic>
    <topic>Routing Technologies
	<topic>Understanding common dynamic routing protocols, including OSPF and EIGRP</topic>
	<topic>Configuring commercial routers</topic>
    </topic>
    <topic>WAN Technologies
	<topic>Understanding the Point-to-Point Protocol</topic>
	<topic>Implementing Point-to-Point Protocol connections with PPP</topic>
    </topic>
    <topic>Infrastructure Services, Security and Management
	<topic>Configuring HSRP and VRRP</topic>
	<topic>Hardening Cisco IOS devices</topic>
	<topic>Managing Switch Operating System files and Startup Configuration files </topic>
    </topic>
  </outline>
</course>
